<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/</title>
   
   <link>/</link>
   <description>introducing Python to chemistry students</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ python_in_chemistry ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ introducing Python to chemistry students ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/assets/images/pic.png</url>
   <title>python_in_chemistry</title>
   <link>/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Python > Excel</title>
	  <link>/saxs-detection-limits</link>
		
				
						<author>Andrew McCluskey</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/saxs-detection-limits</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A friend runs a blog which discusses the use of small-angle scattering (which is also a major area of work for myself. However, today he posted a blog discussing the <a href="http://www.lookingatnothing.com/index.php/archives/2645">minimum concentration of an analyte required to get a good small angle scattering profile</a>.</p>

<p>This blog included a Excel spreadsheet detailing how to preform this calculation. And naturally I was immediately keen to show how this could be performed in Python. So linked below is a Jupyter notebook that uses numpy and pandas to reproduce the work of <a href="http://www.lookingatnothing.com">Brian</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/bjmor    gan/python_in_chemistry/master?filepath=Saxs_Detection_Limits/Saxs_Detection_Limits.ipynb"><img src="https://mybinder.org/badge.svg" alt="Binder" /></a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>pylj Launch</title>
	  <link>/pylj-launch</link>
		
				
						<author>Andrew McCluskey</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/pylj-launch</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><a href="http://pythoninchemistry.org/author/andrew/">Andrew</a> has developed a small teaching utility designed to introduce students to molecular dynamics. He is currently in the process of trying to develop some example applications in the form of laboratory exercises. In the meantime, more information can be found <a href="http://pythoninchemistry.org/pylj">here</a>.</p>

<p>This utility was applied at the ISIS Neutron Training Course as a component of Andrew’s lecture, the material for which can be found in the following post: <a href="http://pythoninchemistry.org/introduction-to-md-ntc">introduction-to-md-ntc</a>.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Introduction to Molecular Dynamics for Neutron Scatters</title>
	  <link>/introduction-to-md-ntc</link>
		
				
						<author>Andrew McCluskey</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/introduction-to-md-ntc</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This year I was invited to take part in the ISIS Neutron Training Course, a introductory course for neutron scattering scientists. The aim of our session was to introduce molecular dynamics and show how this could be applied to neutron scattering experiments. This involved a workshop showing how <a href="http://people.bath.ac.uk/arm61/falass/">falass</a> could be used to analyse neutron reflectometry and an introdcutory lecture outlining molecular dynamics.</p>

<p>To deliver this lecture, I decided to develop a small python utility that performs simple 2D argon simulations and provides visualisation that is both supported by Jupyter and easily extensible. The attached notebook is the result of this course.</p>

<p>It should be noted that due to the computationally intensive nature of MD, I recommend downloading the notebook, installing pylj via pip and running the notebook on your machine. On Window type the following into the Anaconda Prompt, on macOS or Linux type it into the terminal.</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>pip install pylj
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Finally, make sure to also download the additional_code.py file as this makes the plotting easier (make sure that the additional_code.py file is in the same folder as the lecture when you launch the Jupyter notebook).</p>

<p><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bjmorgan/python_in_chemistry/master/Neutron_Training_Course/lecture.ipynb">Download Lecture</a></p>

<p><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bjmorgan/python_in_chemistry/master/Neutron_Training_Course/additional_code.py">Download additional_code</a></p>

<p>(Right click and download the files)</p>

<p>There is currently a server running on which the lecture can be worked through. However, a password is needed, please email Andrew to gain access (arm61 ‘at’ bath.ac.uk). Check that out <a href="http://35.230.133.1/notebook/notebooks/NTC/lecture.ipynb">here</a>.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Blackbody Radiation</title>
	  <link>/blackbody-radiation</link>
		
				
		
				
		
				
						<author>Fiona Dickinson</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blackbody-radiation</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>On the surface this notebook simply exemplfies the use of the <code>np.argmax</code> and <code>np.amax</code> functions, however it also includes a series of other delights:</p>

<ul>
  <li>in addition to using <code>scipy.constants</code> and <code>matplotlib</code>, it shows using colours in the plots;</li>
  <li>using functions is revisited;</li>
  <li><code>print()</code> is joined by an example of created Markdown objects with code, so that units can be presented using LaTeX formatting.</li>
</ul>

<p>Check out the Blackbody Radiation notebook below.</p>

<p><a href="https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/bjmorgan/python_in_chemistry/master?filepath=General%2FBlackbody%20radiation%20maximum%20values.ipynb"><img src="https://mybinder.org/badge.svg" alt="Binder" /></a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
